{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "1. Packed bed reactors are ________ heat exchangers",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Indirect Contact",
        "b": "Direct Contact",
        "c": "Tubular",
        "d": "Plate-type"
      },
    
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which one of the following is not a use of packed bed?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Regenerators",
        "b": "Stripping",
        "c": "Mixing",
        "d": "Solid matrix heat exchangers"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. Why are Packed bed Heat Exchangers Direct contact type heat exchangers?",
      "answers":{
        "a": "Because they create heavy mixing",
        "b":"Uses two fluids to transfer heat by dissolving into each other",
        "c":"Gas liquid system where they are brought to direct contact",
        "d":"Gas-Gas system where they are brought to direct contact"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"c",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"4. The Velocity profile in a packed bed reactor is__________",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Fully parabolic",
        "b":"Parabolic near the walls",
        "c":"Flat at the centre",
        "d":"Concave downward near the walls and upward at the centre"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"5. The pressure drop in a packed bed is _______ for a given length.",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Constant",
        "b":"Exponentially Increasing",
        "c":"Parabolically Increasing",
        "d":"Linearly Increasing"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"d",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"6. The Ergun equation is used to calculate the ___________",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Pressure drop in packed beds",
        "b":"Reynolds number in packed columns",
        "c":"Overall heat transfer coefficients",
        "d":"Number of particles"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"7. In the Ergun equation, what do you understand by the term X? f = ΔP/L X/ρϑS2(∈3/(1-∈))",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Diameter of the tube",
        "b":"Diameter of the pellets",
        "c":"Effective diameter",
        "d":"Equivalent diameter of the tube"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"8. If we have very small dp/di < 0.01, then we may use ____________",
      "answers":{
        "a":"Ergun Equation",
        "b":"Kozeny Carman Equation",
        "c":"Sieder Tate Equation",
        "d":"Arrhenius Equation"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"b",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"9. What is the Reynolds number for the following setup? Density = 990 Kg/m3 Superficial velocity = 10m/s DP = 3mm Porosity = 0.14 Viscosity = 2.5×10-5 kg/ms",
      "answers":{
        "a":"2.76×10^3",
        "b":"2×10^5",
        "c":"0.76×10^5",
        "d":"2.76×10^5"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"d",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    },
    {
      "question":"10. What is the friction factor for the given parameters for a non laminar packed bed setup? Density = 990 Kg/m3 Superficial velocity = 10m/s DP = 3mm Porosity = 0.14 Viscosity = 2.5×10-5kg/ms",
      "answers":{
        "a":"1.751",
        "b":"1.740",
        "c":"1.752",
        "d":"1.749"
      },
      "correctAnswer":"a",
      "difficulty":"beginner"
    }
  ]
}
